Privacy Policy

Last Updated: November 2023

Responsible processing of your personal data is at the core of our concerns. This privacy

policy describes how we process personal data and for what purposes, as well as our use of

cookies.

Subject to the limited exceptions set out below (see section 3), we do not collect personal

data about you. Any personal data we do collect will only be used as permitted by law.

Please read this privacy policy carefully and ensure that you understand it. Your acceptance

of this privacy policy is deemed to occur upon your first use of the Website (as defined in

section 2 below). If you do not accept and agree with this privacy policy, you must stop using

the Website immediately.

1. Definitions

By "processing" personal data, we mean any operation or set of operations which is

performed on personal data or on sets of personal data (e.g., the collection, recording,

storage, use, modification, communication, archiving, deletion, or destruction of personal

data).

By "personal data", we mean any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural

person (e.g., name, date of birth, email address).

The above definitions, and any other legal concept used in this privacy policy, shall, where

applicable, incorporate the definitions provided in the Swiss Data Protection Act ("DPA")

and/or the General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR"), as revised from time to time.

For the sake of readability, only the masculine form is used in this document. It refers to all

individuals, regardless of their gender.

2. Scope

This privacy policy applies to all processing of personal data carried out in connection with

the use of the website www.solarimpulse.com and/or any other website operated by the

Solar Impulse Foundation, its and their subdomains and contents (the "Website").

The Website may contain links to other websites to which this privacy policy does not apply.

If so, please refer to the privacy policy of the respective third party. The Solar Impulse

Foundation has no influence on the data processing by third parties.

3. Collection of Personal Data

a. Contact

If you contact us, such as by sending us an email, we may collect your name and your email

address, as well as any other information which you choose to give us and/or that is

relevant, for the purpose of communicating with you and/or processing your request.

b. World Alliance Membership and Providing of Our Non-Profit Services

The collection of certain personal data is necessary to allow membership in the World

Alliance, for the labeling of solutions and for providing our non-profit services. We may

collect your name and your email address, as well any other information which you choose

to give us and/or that is relevant for these purposes. This data is processed in our legitimate

interest to carry the foregoing.

c. Use of the Website

We collect information in log files when you access the Website. These are logging data

concerning the use of the Website. The following logging data may among others be

processed:

- IP address;

- Date and time of access;

- Volume of transferred data, including the name of the file, etc.;

- Type, version, and language of the browser;

- Operating system and version;

- Pages viewed on the Internet;

- Notification of successful access;

- Information entered in input fields;

- Information about the computer;

- Duration of the visit;

- Click data; and

- Scroll data.

This data is used for statistical and promotional purposes, as well as for the operation and

optimization of the Website. It is processed in our legitimate interest to collect statistical data,

improve our non-profit services and offering of non-profit services, prevent and prosecute

cyber attacks, and deliver and optimize the contents of the Website, as well as our legitimate

promotional interest.

Once you log in to the Website by entering your login, your connection and navigation data

are recorded. This allows us to analyze and evaluate the resulting data to better understand

the browsing habits of our visitors and members to improve the design and usability of the

non-profit services we offer.

d. Newsletters and Emails

The Solar Impulse Foundation uses emails to send personalized information to its members.

We also send confirmation emails for labeling and membership in the form of email

notifications, which are automatically sent to the recipient. For all types of

emails/newsletters, the personal data you have provided (e.g., name, first name, email

address) may be collected to ensure a personalized approach. This data is processed in our

legitimate interest to provide, ensure and improve our non-profit services and offering of non-

profit services, as well as our legitimate promotional interest.

When sending emails, push notifications, or messages through other electronic channels, we

may also collect data about the recipient's response to these messages (e.g., whether an

email or newsletter was received and opened) to identify information of interest and optimize

measures for the recipient. Additionally, it is possible to analyze the use of the Website

accessed through a link provided in the email. This information is used to measure the

success of a campaign. All these evaluations are done in an aggregated form, meaning

without reference to individuals.

Newsletters can be sent with your consent or, in certain circumstances, based on our

legitimate promotional interest. You have the option to unsubscribe from newsletters using

the dedicated link provided in each newsletter.

e. Webinars, E-Pitch and Online Meetings

We organize webinars and e-pitch on specific topics. When you register for such online

meetings, we process the data you enter upon registration (first name, last name, email

address, meeting metadata, etc.). The data provided upon registration is transmitted to the

Solar Impulse Foundation in encrypted form. For this purpose, we generally use the services

of a third-party provider. The Solar Impulse Foundation has no influence on the processing

of your data by this provider. Please refer to their own privacy policy before registering. This

data is processed in our legitimate interest to carry on the relevant webinar and e-pitch, and

to improve our offerings of webinars and e-pitch, as well as for our legitimate promotional

interest.

f. Online Data Aggregation

The Solar Impulse Foundation may, under certain circumstances, receive information about

the use of third-party websites. When you log in to the Website, information about your use

of third-party websites may be associated with your data. This may include:

- Data about your company; and

- Data about the pages viewed.

This data is processed in our legitimate interest to provide, ensure and improve our non-

profit services and offering of non-profit services, as well as our legitimate promotional

interest.

g. Other Purposes

In addition to the above, any collected personal data may be processed for other purposes

set forth in the DPA and/or the GDPR, where applicable, such as the performance of a

contract to which the data subject is party or to take steps at the request of the data subject

prior to entering into a contract, or compliance with a legal obligation

4. Third-Party Data

The personal data we process has mainly been provided by you. However, it may be

supplemented or matched with personal and/or non-personal data from publicly accessible

sources (e.g., the Internet).

5. Electronic Communications

Electronic communications (e.g., email, SMS, social media messaging) are generally not

encrypted. The data transmitted can be intercepted and manipulated by third parties or lost.

The Solar Impulse Foundation implements appropriate technical and organizational security

measures to prevent such events on its systems. However, your device (computer,

smartphone, etc.) and the service used are outside the security perimeter controlled by us.

As an Internet user, it is your responsibility to be informed about the necessary security

measures and take the required steps (e.g., up-to-date antivirus protection).

6. Data Retention Period

The Solar Impulse Foundation processes your personal data for as long as necessary to

achieve the aforementioned purposes and/or for as long as we have your permission to keep

it. Your data is then deleted or anonymized. However, they may continue to be processed,

for example, due to legal retention obligations or as long as rights can be asserted against

the Solar Impulse Foundation. The retention period for personal data depends primarily on

legal prescription periods.

7. Data Security

The Solar Impulse Foundation implements appropriate technical and organizational security

measures to protect your personal data from manipulation, loss, destruction, or access by

unauthorized persons. These measures are based on international standards and are

regularly reviewed and, if necessary, adapted.

8. Data Storage

Your personal data will only be stored in Switzerland. If we do store data outside of

Switzerland, we will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data is treated as safely

and securely, as it would be within Switzerland and under the DPA and/or the GDPR.

9. Data Transfer

In the course of our activities and in pursuing the purposes for which your personal data

were originally collected or may otherwise be lawfully processed, your personal data may be

transferred to the following categories of recipients:

- Our personnel, representatives and agents;

- Our suppliers and services providers, such as our IT systems providers, cloud

services providers;

- Our advisors, such as our legal and financial consultants;

- Any third party to whom we assign or novate any of our rights or obligations; and

- Any third party who needs your personal data in order to allow or confirm your

membership in the World Alliance, the labeling of your solutions, or to allow us to

provide the non-profit services you requested.

Further, we may disclose your personal data to a third party if such disclosure is required by

law, a competent court or a governmental entity, or when we believe in good faith that the

disclosure is necessary to enforce or protect legal or contractual rights and/or to protect your

safety or the safety of others.

10. Rights of Data Subjects

If your personal data is processed by the Solar Impulse Foundation, you can, in accordance

with the DPA and/or the GDPR, as applicable, assert the rights below at any time by sending

us a written request, together with a copy of your ID documents, at dpo@solarimpulse.com

or at the following address:

Solar Impulse Foundation

Chemin de Montolivet 19

1006 Lausanne/VD

Switzerland

Attn: Data Protection Officer

a. Right of Information

You have the right to be informed about our collection and use of your personal data, to the

extent provided for in the DPA and/or the GDPR, as applicable.

b. Right of Access

You have the right to access to the personal data we hold about you, to the extent provided

for in the DPA and/or the GDPR, as applicable.

c. Right to Rectification

The Solar Impulse Foundation strives to ensure that your data is as accurate and up-to-date

as possible. If, despite our efforts, we record incorrect personal data about you, we commit

to correcting it upon your request, to the extent provided for in the DPA and/or the GDPR, as

applicable.

d. Right to Object

You have the right to object to any further processing of your personal data, to the extent

provided for in the DPA and/or the GDPR, as applicable.

e. Right to Erasure

You have the right to request the erasure of your personal data, to the extent provided for in

the DPA and/or the GDPR, as applicable.

f. Right to Limitation of Processing

You have the right to request the limitation of processing of your personal data, to the extent

provided for in the DPA and/or the GDPR, as applicable.

g. Right to Data Portability

Under certain circumstances, you have the right to request that your personal data be

transmitted to you in a common electronic format, to the extent provided for in the DPA

and/or the GDPR, as applicable.

h. Right to Lodge a Complaint

If you have any cause for complaint about our use of your personal data, please contact us

using the details provided in section 12 and we will do our best to solve the problem for you.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the Swiss Federal Data Protection and

Information Officer ("FDPIC") and/or any competent EU supervisory authority, as the case

may be.

i. Rights related to Automated Individual Decision-Making

You have the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing,

including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly

affects you, to the extent provided for in the DPA and/or the GDPR, as applicable.

11. Cookies

The Website uses Cookies and similar technologies to distinguish you from other users.

"Cookies" are small files stored on your device (computer, smartphone, etc.) when you visit

a website. They provide information about the pages visited and the applications you use.

By using Cookies, we are able to make your experience more enjoyable and improve the

Website by better understanding how you use it.

Before Cookies are placed on your computer or device, a pop-up will appear asking you to

consent to the placement of these Cookies. By giving your consent, you enable us to offer

you the best possible use. You may, if you wish, refuse to give your consent to the

placement of Cookies (unless such Cookies are absolutely necessary). In this case, certain

functions of the Website may not be able to be used completely or as intended.

In addition, you can activate or deactivate Cookies in your internet browser. With most

internet browsers, you can also choose to disable all Cookies or only third-party cookies. By

default, most internet browsers are set to accept the majority of Cookies. However, this

setting can be changed. For further details, please refer to the help menu of your internet

browser or the documentation provided. You can remove cookies from your device by

clearing the cookie history of your browser.

The user data collected in this way is pseudonymized and not linked to other personal data.

Linking data to an individual is only possible if the person has clearly identified themselves

(e.g., by using login data) to use the website.

The stored cookies can also be used by cooperating partners or advertising partners.

However, these companies and partners only receive data based on an identification

number called "Cookie ID." No personal data is transmitted to them.

The following first party necessary cookies may be placed on your device:

Name Purpose Duration

\_ALGOLIA Algolia sets this cookie for

the website to function and

cannot be switched off in

our systems.

6 months.

\_\_cf_bm This cookie, set by

Cloudflare, is used to

support Cloudflare Bot

Management.

30 minutes.

\_\_hssc HubSpot sets this cookie to

keep track of sessions and

to determine if HubSpot

should increment the

session number and

timestamps in the __hstc

cookie.

30 minutes.

\_\_hssrc This cookie is set by

Hubspot whenever it

changes the session cookie.

The __hssrc cookie set to 1

indicates that the user has

restarted the browser, and if

the cookie does not exist, it

is assumed to be a new

session.

Session.

PHPSESSID Cookie generated by

applications based on the

PHP language. This is a

general purpose identifier

used to maintain user

session variables. It is

normally a random

generated number, how it is

used can be specific to the

site, but a good example is

maintaining a logged-in

status for a user between

pages.

Session.

The following first party performance, functionality or analytics cookies may be placed on

your device:

Name Purpose Duration

\_fbp Used by Meta to deliver a

series of advertisement

products such as real time

bidding from third party

advertisers.

3 months.

\_ga This cookie name is

associated with Google

Universal Analytics - which

is a significant update to

Google's more commonly

used analytics service. This

cookie is used to distinguish

unique users by assigning a

randomly generated number

as a client identifier. It is

included in each page

request in a site and used to

calculate visitor, session

and campaign data for the

sites analytics reports.

1 year and 1 month.

\_gat_UA-\* This is a pattern type cookie

set by Google Analytics,

where the pattern element

on the name contains the

unique identity number of

the account or website it

relates to. It is a variation of

the _gat cookie which is

used to limit the amount of

data recorded by Google on

high traffic volume websites.

1 minute.

\_ga_5Z3FQDM8CJ This cookie is used by

Google Analytics to persist

session state.

1 year and 1 month.

\_gcl_au Used by Google AdSense

for experimenting with

advertisement efficiency

across websites using their

services.

3 months.

\_gid This cookie is set by Google

Analytics. It stores and

update a unique value for

each page visited and is

used to count and track

pageviews.

1 day.

hubspotutk This cookie name is

associated with websites

built on the HubSpot

platform. HubSpot report

that its purpose is user

authentication.

6 months.

\_\_hstc Hubspot set this main

cookie for tracking visitors. It

contains the domain, initial

6 months.

timestamp (first visit), last

timestamp (last visit),

current timestamp (this

visit), and session number

(increments for each

subsequent session).

\_\_qca This is a cookie usually

associated with Quantcast,

a digital advertising

company. They provide

website rankings, and the

data they collect is also

used for audience

segmentation and targeted

advertising.

1 year.

If you choose to view and use third-party contents on the Website, third-party cookies, such

as those of social media platform, may be placed on your device. The Solar Impulse

Foundation has no influence on the data processing by such third parties. Those third parties

have their own privacy and cookies policies.

Further, the Website uses services from Google Analytics, Hotjar, HubSpot, Facebook Pixel

and Linkedin Insight Tag, as described below. If you do not wish to participate in tracking in

connection with these services, you can object by disabling the storage of cookies through

your browser settings or by enabling the opt-out option.

a. Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc., 1600

Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. Google Analytics uses cookies to

analyze the behavior of website visitors. It provides us with information about the number of

visits, length of visits, and contents viewed, allowing us to continuously improve the Website.

Further information and Google's data protection provisions can be found under Google

Privacy and Google Terms.

b. Hotjar

We use Hotjar, a service provided by Hotjar Ltd, Dragonara Business Centre 5th Floor,

Dragonara Road, Paceville St. Julian's STJ 3141, Malta. It helps us better understand user

experiences (time spent on a website, clicked links, preferences, dislikes, etc.), allowing us

to target based on user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies to collect information about user

behavior and the devices they use. This information is pseudonymized in user profiles and

stored by Hotjar.

c. HubSpot

We use HubSpot, a service provided by HubSpot, Inc., headquartered at 25 First Street,

Cambridge, MA 02141, USA. It is a customer relationship management (CRM) platform that

allows us to better understand and optimize our interactions with members and partners.

Through HubSpot, we can track and analyze user behaviors, such as their interaction with

the Website, content preferences, and more. HubSpot uses cookies to collect this data,

which is then pseudonymously stored in user profiles.

d. Facebook Pixel

We use a "Facebook pixel" from the social network Facebook, Meta Platforms, Inc., One

Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA, to track user behavior when they click on an

advertisement on Facebook. With the Facebook pixel, we can understand how our

promotional measures are received on Meta (formerly Facebook) and take improvement

actions as needed. The tracking duration for users accessing the Solar Impulse Foundation

website by clicking on the advertisements we publish on Facebook can last up to 180 days.

If you wish to disable cookies for Meta, you must adjust your browser settings. More

information on this can be found in your browser's help menu. The data is collected

anonymously and does not allow identification of the user. Meta records and processes the

data for its own advertising purposes, in accordance with Meta Platforms Ireland Limited's

data processing directive (https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).

e. LinkedIn Insight Tag

We use the "LinkedIn Insight Tag" from the social network LinkedIn, operated by LinkedIn

Ireland Unlimited Company, Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland. This tool creates a cookie in

your web browser that records metadata such as IP address, timestamp, and page-related

events (e.g., pages viewed). IP addresses are shortened or hashed (pseudonymized) if they

are used to reach LinkedIn members on all devices. Direct LinkedIn member identifiers are

deleted by LinkedIn after seven days. Other pseudonymized data is deleted within 180 days.

LinkedIn does not share personal data with the website owner but only provides reports and

communications (in which LinkedIn members are not identified) on website audience and

display performance. LinkedIn also offers retargeting of website visitors on LinkedIn,

allowing us to use this data to display targeted ads outside of the Website. You can find

more information on data protection at LinkedIn in their privacy policy.

12. Contact

The owner and operator of the Website is the Solar Impulse Foundation, a foundation

incorporated under the laws of Switzerland, having its registered office at Chemin de

Montolivet 19,1006 Lausanne/VD, Switzerland.

13. Amendment

We may amend this privacy policy from time to time (e.g., if the law changes). Any

amendment will be immediately posted on the Website and you will be deemed to have

accepted the new terms of the privacy policy on your first use of the Website following the

amendment. We recommend that you check this page regularly to keep up-to-date.
